Titian Ramsay Peale Sketches 1817-1875 Mss.B.P31.15d
American Philosophical Society
- Titian Ramsay Peale Sketches, 1817-1875
  - Mink and ermine, [1819-20]; 170; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - The Gigantic Mastodon, 1821 Jan.; 171; Watercolor (wash)
    [Goodman, Am. Nat. His. 2:205]
  - Peacocks eye (fish), Chaetodon ocellatus, 1821 March; 172; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Gull, immature, 1822; 173; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Missouri bear, Ursus horribilis Ord, [1822]; 174; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Piping Plover (Snowy Plover), 1824 May 14; 175; Watercolor, pencil
    [Bonaparte IV:59, Plate .24]
  - Piping Plover, [1824 May]; 176; Watercolor (Box 2)
    [Bonaparte, IV:59, Plate 24]
  - Three birds: 1. Wilson's Phalarope; 2. Shinz's Sandpiper; 3.Piping Plover, [1824]; 177; Watercolor
    [Bonaparte IV: Plate 24]
  - Insects, Plate no. 2, [1824-28]; 178a; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 3, [1824-28]; 178b; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 5, [1824-28]; 178c; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 6, [1824-28]; 178d; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 8, [1824-28]; 178e; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 9, [1824-28]; 178f; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 11, [1824-28]; 178g; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 12, [1824-28]; 178h; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 13, [1824-28]; 178i; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 15, [1824-28]; 178j; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 16, [1824-28]; 178k; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. 17, [1824-28]; 178l; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Insects, Plate no. ?, [1824-28]; 178m; Engraving (Box 2)
  - Mr. Snyder's house, Key Varas, Kinght's Keys... (Florida), 1825 March 14; 179; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Shrew Mole, 1825 July 9; 180; Watercolor (Box 2)
    (For description of' TRP's tamed Shrew Mole, see Goodman, vo1 1: 90-91)
  - Star-nose Mole, [1825 July 9]; 181; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Cerulean Warbler, 1825 Aug. 1; 182a; Watercolor, pencil (Box 2)
  - Bird (unidentified), 1825 Aug. 1; 182b; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Female F. tristis (Female American Goldfinch, [1825]; 183; Pencil (Box 2)
    [See Bonaparte, Am. Orn. Plate 6, fig. 41 (American Goldfinch)]
  - Shrew mole, [1825]; 184; Pencil (Box 2)
    [Goodman, vol. 1, opp.81]
  - "Allentown from the Commodore's house looking north", [1824-25]; 185; Ink & Pencil (Box 2)
  - Sketch of the Peale Museum, [1826/27]; 186a; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Bird (unidentified), [1826/27]; 186b; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Deer, [1827]; 187; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Deer, leaping, [1827]; 188; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Deer, leaping, [1827]; 189; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Two deer (buck & doe), [1827]; 190; Lithograph
  - Two deer (buck & doe) Colored, [1827]; 191; Lithograph
  - Bison, 1829 March 1; 192; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Bison: head & eye "Phila.", 1829 March 2; 193; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Antelope (Gazelle), 1829 June; 194a; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Bird (unidentified), 1829 June; 194b; Watercolor, pencil (Box 2)
  - Antelope (Gazelle), 1829 [June]; 195; Lithograph
  - Antelope (Gazelle), 1829 [June]; 196; Lithograph
  - Wolf and wolf's head "Phila.", 1829 July 22; 197; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Brown wolf (North Carolina), 1829 July 22; 198; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Philadelphia just after a storm, 1829 Aug. 14; 199; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Wolf and wolf's head, 1829 Aug. 14; 200a; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Wolf, 1829 Aug. 14; 200b; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Wolf sleeping "taken with the camera lucida", 1829 Aug. 14; 201a; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Wolf sleeping "taken with the camera lucida", 1829 Aug. 14; 201b; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Wolf sleeping "taken with the camera lucida", 1829 Aug. 14; 202; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Wolf, [1829 Aug.]; 203; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Polar bear, 1830 Jan. 3; 204; Watercolor, pencil (Box 2)
  - Polar bear, [1830]; 205; Pencil tracing (Box 2)
  - Polar bear, sitting, [1830]; 206a; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Cat head, [1830]; 206b; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Polar bears, [1830]; 207; Oil
  - Bangor, Maine, [1830 Oct.]; 208; Pencil (Box 2)
  - "Bark canoe, Maine Indians", [1830 Oct.]; 209; Watercolor, pencil (Box 2)
  - Camp in Maine woods, [1830 Oct.]; 210; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Camp in Maine woods, [1830 Oct.]; 211; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Camp in Maine woods, [1830 Oct.]; 212; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Mitchele Louis, Penobscot Indian, [1830 Oct.]; 213; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Penobscot Indian, [1830 Oct.]; 214; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Jo Socceus, Penobscot Indian, [1830 Oct.]; 215; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Cabin in Maine woods, [1830 Oct.]; 216; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Moose & description, [1830 Oct.]; 217; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Moose head, [1830 Oct.]; 218; Pencil (Box 2)
  - Moose, with measurements, [1830 Oct.]; 219; Pencil (Box 2)
  - "Long Beach, N.J., Duck shooting", [1830]; 220; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - King Vulture (bird), Turbaco, New Grenada (condor), [1830]; 221; Watercolor (Box 2)
  - Bird (diagram), [1830]; 222; Pencil (Box 3)
    [See Cabinet of Nat. His. & Am. Rural Sports, 1830, vol. 1., 203]
  - Lizard, Magdaline River, So. America, [1830]; 223; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Grasshopper, 1831 April 4; 224; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Falls of Tiquendama; near Bogata, New Grenada, [1831 June]; 225a; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Soldier, [1831 June]; 225b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Saddle, [1830-32]; 226a; Pencil (Box 3)
    [Sketched while in So. America]
  - Torso, (human), [1830-32]; 226b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Saddle stirrup, [1830-32]; 227; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Spear, [1830-32]; 228a; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Torso (arm & head), [1830-32]; 228b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Iguana, [1830-32]; 229; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Design for coin, "Liberty", 1832; 230; Watercolor, ink, pencil (Box 3)
  - Three birds: 1. Glossy Ibis; 2. Pectorial Sand-piper; 3. Red-Breasted Snipe, [1833]; 231; Watercolor
    [See Bonaparte, Am. Orn. 1833, v. IV, Plate 23]
  - Three birds: 1. Glossy Ibis; 2. Pectorial Sand-piper; 3. Red-Breasted Snipe, [1833]; 232; Watercolor
  - Three moths, [1833]; 233a; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Three moths, [1833]; 233b; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Monarch butterfly (colored) with caterpillar, [1833]; 233c; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Moths: Saturnia promethea, Female (colored), [1833]; 233d; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Two moths: Saturnia promethea, male (colored), [1833]; 233e; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Three moths, caterpillar & chrysalis (colored), [1833]; 233f; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Butterflies, caterpillar & chrysalis: Xanthidia lisa (colored), [1833]; 233g; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Two moths, caterpillar & chrysalis: Geometra domestica (colored), [1833]; 233h; Lithograph (Box 3)
  - Sea Gull, Procellario carpensis, 1834 Mar. 18; 234; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Black tailed or Mule Deer, Cervus macrotis, 1834; 235; Lithograph (Box 3)
    [See: The Advocate of Science and the Ann. of Nat. History, 1834. vol. 1, p.11 (Film 13)]
  - Design for coin (Eagle), [1835-36]; 236; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Design for coin (Eagle), [1835-36]; 237; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Design for coin (Eagle), [1835-36]; 238; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Design for coin (Eagle), [1835-36]; 239; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Design for coin or medallion, [1835-36]; 240; Oil (Box 3)
  - Eagle & deer, [1835-36]; 241a; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Rifle, "Dr. Robert Patterson", [1835-36]; 241b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Design for coin or medallion (eagle), [1835-36]; 242; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Design for coin or medallion (eagle), [1835-36]; 243; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Rabbit, Lepus palustris, [1836]; 244; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Rabbit, "Lepus Americanus", 1836; 245; Lithograph (Box 3)
    [Lith. Lehman & Duval, Phila.]
  - Madeira, from the Summit of Coural Das Freira, [1838 Sep. 18]; 246; Watercolor
  - Outrigger canoes, Madeira, [1838 Sep.]; 247; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Tern, Brown Hoddy, 1838 Nov. 2; 248; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Bats, "off the Coast of Brazil", 1838 Nov. 18; 249; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - "Rio Janeiro, Rue Direche", 1838 Nov.; 250; Pencil
  - Porpoise, "Corrected by Lt. [Wm. M.] Walker", [1839 Jan. 18]; 251; Pencil
  - Dolphin: "Delphinus pectoralis" (with notes), [1839 Jan. 18]; 252a; Pencil (Box 3)
    [See: John Cassin, Mammology and Ornithology of Wilkes Expedition, 1858, Plate No.5 (Dolphin)]
  - Dolphin (back view), [1839 Jan. 18]; 252b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Guanaco, Rio Negro, Patagonia, 1839 Jan.; 253; Pencil (Box 3)
  - "Pilot's house, Rio Negro, Patagonia", [1839 Jan.]; 254; Pencil (Box 3)
  - "Cape Pigeon" (bird) with sketch of boat, [1839 Feb.]; 255; Pencil (Box 3)
  - U.S. Schooner Sea Gull, on bar of Rio Negro, 1839 [Jan.]; 256; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Goose (with notations), 1839 Feb. 21; 257; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Bird (Bunting?) (with notations), 1839 Feb. 22; 258; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Wolf [drawn by Thomas T. Craven?], 1839 Feb.-Mar.; 259; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Wolf "Orange Bay" (Tierra del Fuego). T. T. Craven, 1839 March; 260; Watercolor
  - Albatross: "Diomedea fuliginosa", 1839 March 14; 261; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Storm Petrel, "Blue Petral, male", 1839 March 18; 262; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Storm Petrel ?, 1839 March 21; 263; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Diomedea exulans (Albatross), 1839 April 7; 264; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Crested bird (Passerine bird), 1839 May 28; 265; Watercolor (wash) (Box 3)
  - Male wolf, "Cordillera de los Andes", 1839 May; 266; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Female fox, "Road to Santiago, Chili", 1839 May; 267; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Mound near Lima, Peru, 1839 [June]; 268; Ink & wash (Box 3)
  - Mound near Lima, Peru, 1839 [June]; 269; Oil
  - Llamas (Peru?), [1839 June]; 270; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Luca Tern (bird) at Callao, near Lima, Peru, 1839 July 1; 271; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Fairy Tern (Gygis), [1839 Aug.]; 272; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Frigate-bird, sp., 1839 Aug. 16; 273; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Red-footed Booby, 1839 Aug. 21; 274; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Tahiti, "Moatoa" [Valley of the Popino River], 1839 [Aug-Sep]; 275; Ink & pencil (Box 3)
  - Tahiti, "First camp on the Popenoo river", 1839 [Aug.-Sep.]; 276; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Church, Popenoo, Tahiti, 1839 [Aug.-Sep.]; 277; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Tahiti, "North side of Tahiti" (landscape), 1839 Sep.; 278; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Ptilonapus purpuratus, or Fruit Pigeon, 1839 Sept. 8; 279; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Columba oceanica (Pigeon), 1839 Sept; 280; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Carpophaga aurorce (Pigeon), [1839 Sept.]; 281; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Shearwater sp. (?) [Bird], "Tahiti", [1839 Sept.]; 282; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Meliphagid sp., 1839 Oct. 19; 283; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Didunculus strigirostrus, Samoa (pigeon), [1839]; 284; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Tahitian Indian, "Homai", 1839; 285; Pencil (Box 3)
  - "Taunoa (village), Tahiti", [1840 June]; 286; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Feejee (Fiji) canoe, [1840 Jan.-June]; 287; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Cormorant sp. (bird), 1840 March 8; 288; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Magellanic penguin ?, 1840 March; 289; Pencil (Box 3)
  - "Viti canoe skulling" Fiji, [1840 May-June]; 290; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Taunoa (village), Tahiti, John's House, [1840 June]; 291; Oil
  - Pigeon sp., 1840 Aug. 6; 292; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Mauna Loa (volcano), Hawaii, [1840 Fall]; 293; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Mauna Loa (volcano), Hawaii, [1840 Dec.]; 294; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Mauna Loa (volcano), Hawaii, [1840 Dec.]; 295; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Antarctic Ice (Ship, from the Wilkes Exp.), [1840]; 296; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Tree near which Capt. Cook was killed, Keala kua Bay, Hawaii, [1840 Dec.]; 297; Pencil (Box 3)
    [See: Wilkes' Narrative 1849; IV:93]
  - Tree near which Capt. Cook was killed, [1840 Dec.]; 298; Photograph (Box 3)
    [Photo of painting owned by Ed. L. Lachman, St. Pete., 1970]
  - Peale's River, Vitia lern, [1840]; 299; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Prisoners on island of Samboangu?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 300; Watercolor (Box 3)
    Artist unknown
  - Philippine woman?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 301; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Philippine man?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 302; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Prisoners on Samboangu?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 303; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Prisoners on Samboangu?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 304; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Prisoners on Samboangu?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 305; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Prisoners on Samboangu?, [1841 Jan. 28]; 306; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers, [1841 Jan. 31]; 307; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers & butterfly, [1841 Jan. 31]; 308; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers & butterfly, [1841 Jan. 31]; 309; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers & butterfly, [1841 Jan. 31]; 310; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers & butterfly, [1841 Jan. 31]; 311; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Flowers & butterfly, [1841 Jan. 31]; 312; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Albatross sp. ("Diomedea brachyura"), 1841 May 20; 313; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Diomedea brachyura (Albatross sp.), 1841 May 26; 314; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Ship, Peacock ?, [1841June-Jul.]; 315; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Fort Sutter ?, [1841 Oct.]; 316a; Watercolor
  - Plan of Fort Sutter ?, [1841 Oct. 19]; 316b; Watercolor
  - Common gallinule, [1841]; 317; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - "Catching wild geese in California", [1841]; 318; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Palm trees, Manila, 1842 [Jan.]; 319; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Palm tree, Manila, 1842 [Jan.]; 320; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Brown Albatross, [1838-42]; 321; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Black-headed gull, [1838-42]; 322; Pencil (Box 3)
  - American White Pelican, [1838-42]; 323; Watercolor (Box 3)
  - Snowy Plover, [1838-42]; 324; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Black-fronted tern, [1838-42]; 325; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Black-fronted tern, [1838-42]; 326a; Watercolor, pencil (Box 3)
  - Black-fronted tern, [1838-42]; 326b; Pencil (Box 3)
  - Tern sp., [1838-42]; 327a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Tern sp. (head), [1838-42]; 327b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Toucan sp., [1838-42]; 328a; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Toucan beak, [1838-42]; 328b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Durlin (bird), ("Tringa alpinus"), [1838-42]; 329; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Sandpiper sp., [1838-42]; 330a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Sandpiper sp., [1838-42]; 330b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Sandpiper sp., [1838-42]; 331a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Sandpiper sp., [1838-42]; 331b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Swan sp. "from Mr. Heads specimen", [1838-42]; 332; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Willet (bird), [1838-42]; 333; Watercolor
  - Fish (with notations), [1838-42]; 334; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Mouth of the river Bogie ?, [1838-42]; 335; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Man in cabin, [1838-42]; 336; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ship, Flying Fish, [1838-42]; 337; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ship, Porpoise, [1838-42]; 338; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ships, Porpoise and Flying Fish, [1838-42]; 339; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ships, Porpoise and Flying Fish, [1838-42]; 340; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ships in a harbor, [1838-42]; 341; Ink (Box 4)
  - Ships on the horizon, [1838-42]; 342; Pencil (Box 4)
  - View of shoreline from a barge, [1838-42]; 343a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Building, objects (faint sketches), [1838-42]; 343b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - View of shoreline & ships from a barge, [1838-42]; 344; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Wolves. 1. Lupus gigas 2. Lupus occidentalis, [1838-42]; 345; Pencil
    [Cassin's i.d. See: Cassin, Plate No.3]
  - Wolves. 1. Lupus gigas 2. Lupus occidentalis, [1838-42]; 346; Oil
  - Wilson's storm Petrel (bird) By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Jan. 7; 347; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Shearwater sp. By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Jan. 7; 348a; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Foot of Shearwater sp. By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Jan. 7; 348b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Shearwater sp. By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Jan. 22; 349; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Proscelaria (Sea gull head). By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Feb. 13; 350; Watercolor,ink, Pencil
  - Oystercatcher sp. By Joseph Drayton, 1839 Feb.; 351; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Rail sp. (bird), Rallus olivaceus. By Joseph Drayton, 1839 March 9; 352; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Caiacaia (bird). By Joseph Drayton, 1839 April 1; 353; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Unidentified bird. By Joseph Drayton, 1841 May; 354; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - Eider sp. (bird) By Joseph Drayton, 1841 May; 355; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Frog spawn, Rock Creek, D.C., 1849 April 8; 356; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Great-falls, Potomac River, 1858; 357; Oil
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 July 2l; 358; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 July 23; 359; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Ju1y 30; 360; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Aug. 2; 361; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Aug. 2; 362; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Aug, 5; 363; Oil (Box 4)
  - 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Aug. 5; 364; Oil (Box 4)
  - Fish Hawks nest, 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1873 Aug.; 365; Oil (Box 4)
    [with 3p. AD]
  - Forest scene, [1873]; 366; Oil (Box 4)
  - Forest scene, [1873]; 367; Oil (Box 4)
  - Flower, 7 mile Beach, N.J., 1875 Aug. 8; 368; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - Animal skulls & bones, n.d.; 369; Charcoal (Box 4)
  - Animal skull, n.d.; 370; Charcoal (Box 4)
  - Animal skull, n.d.; 371; Charcoal (Box 4)
  - Animal skull, n.d.; 372; Charcoal (Box 4)
  - Animal skull, n.d.; 373; Watercolor & charcoal (Box 4)
  - Animal skull (Deer), n.d.; 374; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Animal bones, n.d.; 375; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - Bobwhites (?), n.d.; 376; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Bobwhite (?), n.d.; 377; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Bobwhite (?), n.d.; 378; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Chickens, n.d.; 379; Engraving (Box 4)
  - Blackbilled cuckoo, n.d.; 380; Watercolor
  - Duck, n.d.; 381; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - Duck (American Wigeon?) "Charleston Museum Nov. 16, 1824 (No. 1)", n.d.; 382; Watercolor, pencil
  - Duck dissection of neck, n.d.; 383; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Bird (Finch?), n.d.; 384; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Bird (Finch?), n.d.; 385; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Frigate Bird (male), n.d.; 386; Engraving (Box 4)
  - American purple Gallinule (bird), n.d.; 387; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Ruffled Grouse, n.d.; 388; Pencil
  - Ruffled Grouse, n.d.; 389; Pencil
  - Ruffled Grouse, n.d.; 390; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Heath Grouse, n.d.; 391; Pencil (Box 4)
    [See Poesch, p.116, Fig.55]
  - Heath Grouse, n.d.; 392; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ostrich, n.d.; 393; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Finch, "Loxia nigra", n.d.; 394; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Blackbird (Leteridae?), n.d.; 395; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Parrots, n.d.; 396; Pencil (Box 4)
  - White Pelican, American, n.d.; 397; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Copper beaked Pigeon, n.d.; 398; Watercolor, pastel?
  - Prairie Hen, n.d.; 399; Pencil
  - Quail, n.d.; 400; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Ringnecked Duck (?), n.d.; 401; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - New world vulture, n.d.; 402; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Woodpecker sp., n.d.; 403; Watercolor, pencil (Box 4)
  - Arctia (Spilosoma) [plant], n.d. [July 5]; 404; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Flower (Columbine?), n.d.; 405; Oil (Box 4)
  - Swamp Dogwood with caterpillars, n.d.; 406; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Fir tree, with building, n.d.; 407; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Honeysuckle, n.d.; 408; Oil (Box 4)
  - Tulip tree & swallowtail butterflies, n.d.; 409; Oil (Box 4)
  - Bush branches, n.d.; 410; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Blossoms & leaves (practice sketches), n.d.; 411; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Blossoms & leaves (practice sketches), n.d.; 412a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Blossoms & leaves (practice sketches), n.d.; 412b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Leaves (practice sketches), n.d.; 413; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Leaves (practice sketches), n.d.; 414; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Leaves, n.d.; 415a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Building, n.d.; 415b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Leaves, n.d.; 416; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Plants (practice sketches), n.d.; 417; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Practice sketches (leaves & trees), n.d.; 418; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Shrub, n.d.; 419; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Flower, n.d.; 420a; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Cliff, n.d.; 420b; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Bush & tree, n.d.; 421; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Tree trunk & branches, n.d.; 422; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Trees, n.d.; 423; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Tree trunks & branches, n.d.; 424; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Flowers, n.d.; 425; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Maple tree, n.d.; 426; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Hesperia albicollis, n.d.; 427; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Leaves (tracing ?), n.d.; 428; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Fish, n.d.; 429; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Fish, Cephalopterus vampyrus, Cape May, n.d.; 430; Watercolor (Box 4)
  - Beetle, n.d.; 431; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Chrysalis (cocoon), n.d.; 432; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Katydid, n.d.; 433; Pencil (Box 4)
  - Landscape, with river and fort ?, 434; Watercolor (Box 5)
  - Landscape, "View of Cooper Creek N. Jersey", 435a; Watercolor (Box 5)
  - Sailboat, n.d.; 435b; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape: curved mountain road, 436; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape: mountain view, 437; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape: river & foliage, 438; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape: river & woods, 439; Watercolor (Box 5)
  - Landscape: shoreline and plants, 440; Watercolor, pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape: tree on river bank with boat, 441a; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Profile of man (C. W. Peale?), n.d.; 441b; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Tree, boulder, plants, n.d.; 442; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Landscape, water pouring over a dam, 443; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Three birds, n.d.; 444; Lithograph (Box 5)
    1. Hummingbird; 2. Parrot; 3. ?
  - Three birds, n.d.; 445; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Three birds (colored), n.d.; 446; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Buffaloe, n.d.; 447; Lithograph
  - Moose, n.d.; 448; Engraving
  - Snails (Childs & Inman's Lithograph), n.d.; 449; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Directions for Collecting and Preserving Objects of Natural History (Title page), 450; Lithograph (Box 5)
    Circular of the Phila. Museum containing Directions for..., 1831. [APS 500 Pam. v.4]
  - United Bowman insignia, n.d.; 451; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - United Bowman insignia, n.d.; 452; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Prong-Horned Antelope, n.d.; 453; Lithograph (Box 5)
    (Alex Rider, Childs & Lehm)
  - Bird (unidentified) By William W. Wood, n.d.; 454; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Bird (unidentified) By William W. Wood, n.d.; 455; Lithograph (Box 5)
  - Portrait of Lt. Col. William Washington, n.d.; 456; Watercolor (Box 5)
  - Self-portrait ?, three poses, n.d.; 457; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Three people beside a creek, n.d.; 458; Ink (Box 5)
  - Man beside tent & camp fire, n.d.; 459; Ink (Box 5)
  - Animal anatomy, n.d.; 460; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Antelope, n.d.; 461; Pencil
  - Cattle, n.d.; 462; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Cattle, n.d.; 463; Ink & wash (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 464; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer (fawn), n.d.; 465; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 466; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 467; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 468; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 469; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 470; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 471; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 472; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 473; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer (headless), n.d.; 474; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 475; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 476; Pencil (Box 5)
    Note: "Audubon pl. [136], vol.3"
  - Deer by a lake, n.d.; 477a; Ink & wash (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 477b; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 478; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 479; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 480; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Deer, n.d.; 481; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Moose, n.d.; 482; Pencil
  - Deer (buck), n.d.; 483; Pencil
  - Deer (buck), n.d.; 484; Pencil
  - Deer, n.d.; 485; Pencil (Othertype Extra OS)
  - Deer, n.d.; 486; Pencil (Box 5)
    By Felix [Octavius Carr] Daley
  - Elephant, n.d.; 487; Ink & wash (Box 5)
  - Goats, n.d.; 488; Ink & wash (Box 5)
  - Goats, n.d.; 489; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Horses, n.d.; 490; Ink & wash (Box 5)
  - Monkey ("Simia hamadryas, Tartarian Monkey"), n.d.; 491; Watercolor (Box 5)
  - Moose, n.d.; 492; Pencil
  - Moose, n.d.; 493a; Ink (Box 5)
  - Moose, n.d.; 493b; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Moose (head), n.d.; 494; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Moose (head). "1st Camera tracing" (camera lucida), n.d.; 495a; Pencil
  - Moose (head). "2 Camera tracing" (camera lucida), n.d.; 495b; Pencil
  - Moose (head), n.d.; 496; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Moose, n.d.; 497; Pencil (Othertype Extra OS)
  - Moose, n.d.; 498; Pencil (Othertype Extra OS)
  - Rabbits, n.d.; 499; Oil
  - Ram's head, n.d.; 500; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Sheep, Bighorn, n.d.; 501; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Sheep, Bighorn, n.d.; 502; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Sheep, Bighorn, n.d.; 503; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Sheep, Bighorn, n.d.; 504; Pencil (Box 5)
  - Sheep hoof?, n.d.; 505; Pencil (Box 5)